My name is Jason Vaught
in 2014 I was convicted of distributing
millions of pain pills in a drug
conspiracy and this is how crime works.
The George brothers American pain they
were our competition and we stole their
patient list so we got all their contact
information. I walk into the office and
our people are just making phone calls
and they're telling them hey this is
American pain all out state patients are
going to be going to Jacksonville pain
from here on out if you show back up at
American pain in West Palm Beach you'll
be discharged. The next day I just see
two vehicles pull up to the front door a
Range Rover and Mercedes. I said so get
ready so we grabbed our guns and the
doors open all these dudes come in so I
pull out a gun and I put it to his head
and he actually calls the cops on me.
So they start investigating us.
What is a pill mill? The business that
is a front it's a white coat doctor
front for a drug business. All they're
saying is that we're hiding behind a
doctor's coat to run pills
rather than you see a drug dealer on the
corner we're actually putting drug
dealers in lab coats. I hate the word
pill mill the reason why is I didn't
feel like I ran a pill mill I ran a
business that the government allowed me.
A pain management clinic is a business
just like a doctor's office so you go
see a doctor and they treat you with
medicine rather than through like a
chiropractor or surgery you're going to
try pain management which is Oxycodone
Percocet's Vicodin stuff like that. I
was in the cocaine business during the
2000s beginning of 09-ish somewhere in
there I was done. During my cocaine days
I had a close friend of mine that I grew
up with Zach Rose. 3-4 months after I
got out of the cocaine my phone rings
and he says listen dude I went to a
strip club last night and there's this
guy in there just absolutely just
blowing tons of money. He owns all these
pain clinics
and his name is Vinnie Colangelo Vincent
Colangelo. I was telling that I already
doctor shop at his clinics and I bring a
bunch of people and all this other stuff
and he's like, "Dude, you need to get
out of that. You need to come and invest
with me and and let's run this
operation." And he's like, "Everything
that he's got going on like it's it it's
legal. You can put the money in the bank
like you know, you got to get your
license, you got to set everything up.
It's all legal." And then he takes me by
one of the clinics,
uh Vinnie's clinic off of Commercial
Boulevard 995 down in Fort Lauderdale.
Walk inside and they got all like
certificates and all the things on the
wall and doctors and patients and like
it's chaotic and I'm like, "This is
crazy. This thing is running downtown
Fort Lauderdale right in front of
everybody. Cops are driving by." You go
inside, they've got like a waiting room
with the windows and a hallway to the
doctor's offices and you know, and all
this stuff and
in-house dispensary. So, you could see
the doctor and get your pills in the
same spot. Like it's not a normal
doctor's office. So, I'm like sitting
and looking at this stuff. So, now the
wheels are turning. I'm like,
"This is crazy. Like this is absolutely
crazy." He's like, "Trust me, we're
going to do it the right way." So, I'm
like, "Okay.
I'm in. I like these words. As long as
we're going to do it right." He says,
"Jason, we're going to do it right."
I gave him money to invest in with um
Vinnie to uh invest into his clinics. He
had so much money, but he needed another
50,000. Zach's plan was he's like,
"Jason, I'm going to make a copy of
every form, learn this in and out,
everything. I've already started the
process."
He said, "I'm going to stay around long
enough to figure out the ins and outs
and we're going to go do our own thing.
We're going to do it legit and not have
to worry about this stress and worry
about if the doors are going to get
kicked in because of all this drug
activity going on. In Florida, they had
the rules the laws where you could have
a pain clinic and then run in-house
dispensary under the doctor's 222 forms.
So, they could order pills and sell them
in the same location.
So, it was a win-win. We write the
scripts, right? And they go to CVS and
Walgreens.
If there's an employee there that is
just absolutely against this,
they're reporting you, they're calling
law enforcement, they're declining to
give your patients meds when the doctor
is a legit doctor is allowed to do it.
They can decline it.
So, it's red flag in the business. So,
having an in-house dispensary, you
eliminate that. You control everything.
So, you write the scripts and sell them
without nobody else knowing what's going
on and how much pills they're getting.
We have high school diplomas, no college
degree.
We don't know nothing about the medical
field.
So, eventually we pull the plug and
we're ready to go. So, we go to
Jacksonville, Florida. And the reason
why we go to Jacksonville is because
in South Florida is where all the
competition is. Everybody's doing it in
South Florida. Well, everybody's coming
Most of the people are coming from out
of state.
Tennessee, Kentucky, Ohio, Virginia. All
that's the biggest hub. I mean, they're
coming from all over the place, but your
biggest hub is that area. So, we were
thinking like, why don't we cut them
off? Save them 6 hours from state line
to Fort Lauderdale. 6 hours back 12.
We're like, Jacksonville, perfect. Soon
as Vinny found out what we're doing, he
cut Zach off and didn't pay us, buy us
out, or nothing. We lost everything that
we had there, which was fine. Whatever.
We had some money I had money put away.
So, I invest even more money into
Jacksonville Pain. It's the first one we
start.
Back then, they were getting doctors off
Craigslist. And so, what we did is we we
ran an ad, we got the building, we built
it out cuz we wanted it built out so
case a doctor want to see it, we can
show him.
So, we run some ads, we get a bunch of
hits. We're creating these medical
facilities. We're going to
We're going to do is we're going to
lease the room to these doctors. That's
going to be our selling point. Like,
we're not doctors. We're just We're
going to put the money in the buildings,
the advertisement. We're going to bring
patients to you. You're just going to
rent the room.
And it worked. You have a lot of doctors
that are
60, 70, 80 years old, okay? They had
great practices, they made a lot of
money, they didn't know how to manage
the money like most doctors don't. They
were just family doctors.
And their practices went under, or they
got a divorce, or they were running low
on money, or they needed a part-time
job, and they wanted to make more money.
They were an employee of Jacksonville
Pain, we 1099 them, they're
subcontractors in a way. Each doctor
uh has a 224 register so they can fill
out to the DEA to get medicine.
So we would use their 22 forms and we'd
pay them extra money to be able to house
medication in our in-house dispensary.
So we'd have to give them a cut of it.
Pharmaceutical companies distributors
will only give them so much per doctor.
Like it's like one of those things where
if I owned a pharmacy, I can get
unlimited amount of pills. But in a
in-house dispensary, they're kind of
like, "Ah, you know, like it's not
monitored that well, we don't want to
give you too much." So you have to build
a relationship with these people. There
was an unspoken rule like, "Don't
prescribe more than 240 pills per
patient for a month."
An average doctor probably sees 25, 35
patients, and a higher-end doctor will
see around 40, 50 patients a day. We
want to stay within these guidelines,
and people are like, "Well, you're just
doing it to like a cover to for your
drug operation." I mean, you could say
it either way, however you want to look
at it.
But I never once told our doctors what
to prescribe, what they could and
couldn't, or how much to prescribe. We
charged extra for them to fill pills in
our our dispensary because they're going
to pay extra to have the scrutiny to
guarantee they'd be filled their
scripts. Writing the scripts
pays the bills.
The in-house dispensary is 100% profit.
So if you didn't have an in-house
dispensary, you wouldn't make very much
money, maybe six to nine thousand
dollars a day. I mean, that's a lot of
money. But not a hundred thousand
dollars a day. The scripts would cover
paying the building, overhead,
employees, pay the doctors, buy the
medication. All of it by writing the
scripts. Literally 100% profit of the
pills. We had an ex-DEA agent over the
pharmaceutical part. He was 20 years in
on the DEA. He retired, became a
consultant. He like understood what the
DEA was looking for in the rules because
this stuff was so vague, it was not even
funny. There was no black and white
print of what you can and can't do.
So, nobody knew what the rules were.
Nobody knew what the law was. Every day
we're doubling. So, first day, say we
had 50 people at the door. Next day we
had 100 people waiting at the door.
Before you know it, with the weekend, we
got before we get there at 6:00 7:00 in
the morning, there's already 200 people
lined up out in front of this place and
we can't control it. We have to hire a
round-the-clock security. I knew that
this stuff was bad and I knew it what
was doing. But, what separates me from
Big Pharma
or whoever approves me to do it. If
you're going to allow me to do something
and give me a license to do it,
for somebody that has a mindset like me,
I'm going to do it. I'm not proud of it.
But, I'm a criminal.
Does that make sense?
The person that was using the pills is
50/50 guilty.
They They came to me, I prescribed them.
That's 50/50. Just like in the coke
business. I had the product. I didn't
put nothing in nobody's head and say,
"Do this." They came to me. That's a
50/50 transaction. I'm half the problem,
they're the other half.
So, you can't put a You can't put more
blame on me as the person that's using
it.
When we first
started building it out, we wasn't
advertising, we weren't doing nothing
because we were trying to still collect
money from Vinny's operations and not
get screwed out of it and still be in
there to learn as much as possible. And
what we did was the George brothers,
American Pain. Uh they were our
competition. So, me and Zach were like,
"I don't know who these dudes are, but
uh they're the biggest in industry.
Let's steal their patient list. Let's
show them who's the boss is in town, the
new warden. This is where I our
young minds, dumb minds come into play.
So, we are going to hire a stripper to
go in and work there and print the list
out. Come to find out that was
impossible [clears throat] because too
many eyes inside.
Wasn't able to do it. We found out where
they were getting all their MRIs. So,
they worked a deal with this guy named
Pete Tindell. He owned a portable MRI
machine. So, it was a semi-rig.
And he would put it behind strip club
parking lots and places that where he
could run it 24 hours a day. And strip
clubs are open all night and nobody
would pay attention during the daytime.
So, people would go there 24 hours and
get scanned and he would send them over
to Thailand, Philippines, they would
read them, come back and he would print
them out. Come to find out majority of
them were fake. People were paying extra
to get fake MRIs. They're all the same
MRIs. He did all of American Pain's
MRIs.
So, we worked a deal with Pete to give
us his patient list, everybody who went
to American Pain.
So, we got all their contact
information. We were going to call them
and just say, "Hey, listen, we're a new
pain clinic. We open up in Jacksonville.
We could save you 12-hour round trip.
You don't have to go to South Florida no
more, blah blah blah."
Now,
I walk into the office and they're all
got their feet kicked up on the dash and
they're just making phone calls, like
six of them. And they're telling them,
"Hey, this is American Pain. All the
outside patients are going to
Jacksonville. We're going to save you a
round trip. We're going to do this, blah
blah blah. You're going to get the same
thing you were getting down there,
everything else." Everybody was like,
"Wow, like we're you know, they were so
happy, couldn't wait." And the first day
that we finally opened, we show up like
8:00 in the morning to open the doors
and there's already 50 people in line at
the front door. And the George brothers
realized that a lot of people didn't
show up, so they started calling them.
And they realized that they're like,
"Oh, no, we're at your pain clinic in
Jacksonville." And they're like, "What
are you talking about?" But the very
next day,
they tried to send somebody through.
Um we caught them, kicked them out. I
followed them down the road, seen them
get in the car of George brother,
Chris George, in his car.
And I came back and I told Zach, I was
like, um,
that's one of
Chris George's people. I said, "So, get
ready." So, we grabbed our guns and the
doors open, all these dudes come in and,
um, they, um,
were asking for Zach. Zach was behind
the counter. They ran up, Chris ran up
to him, they started to getting into it.
The other three guys were out in the
hallway with me and they were running
their mouths, threatening, saying
they're going to do all this stuff and I
just started laughing. He asked me what
I'm laughing at and he's like, "I got
something for you." And he acts like
he's digging in his pocket. So, I pull
out a gun and I put it to his head.
And he actually calls the cops on me.
Feds show up, they take them to jail
and they tell them that that is their
pain clinic, that they invested money in
and that they went in there extorting
us, that
they were supposed to we were supposed
to pay them their percentage, they were
there to collect money. So, the Feds are
thinking like, "How do we miss this
clinic? Like, what do you mean? We've
been watching them and we don't know
anything about this clinic?" So, they
start investigating us.
We thought it was kind of funny that
we're going to hire like hot chicks to
run the front desk.
So,
Zach and I put an ad on Craigslist
saying $20 medical office job an hour,
send pic. Which you can't get away with
that today. I didn't realize it was
going to be the worst thing that we ever
did also. The girls were accepting
bribes, you couldn't control them. Guys
would come up and be like, "Hey, I want
to to, um,
I want to pay 50 bucks or $100 to bump
my file to the top
of the list. Well, if guy after guy does
it, so the guy that started bumping the
second or third, he keeps going down cuz
they keep putting more things. So, now
this guy's complaining. So, I fired all
the girls.
And, um, we brought in somebody else to
manage and like that. Zach came in, got
mad, fired all them, brought the girls
back and that's when I knew that was
just going wrong. Zach had told me, he
was like, "Jason, I had to do what we
had to do." And Zach was just like, took
money from everybody and was promising
everybody the world. He just lied, he
didn't care, he just wanted to ride
around in his Ferraris and Lamborghinis
and helicopters. Zach wants to be the
top dog. He doesn't want nobody else
above him, nobody had more than him.
So, he wants everybody to look up to
him. So, he's the type of person that
takes money from
10 different people, gives everybody 10
different pieces, but he's the hub.
There was this guy named Roland
that was in my indictment, and he was
brought in through somebody else that
invested from down south. He knew the
ins and outs. He's the one that had the
connects with the pharmaceutical
companies. You couldn't get it an
account with them without somebody
referring you and getting you in the
door. When we were having so many
problems and we couldn't keep a
Jacksonville clean and running right cuz
Zach worked against us every which way
we could.
So, they brought in Roland to clean up
the operations. Fire everybody, clean
everything. Roland fired everybody. Zach
was mad cuz he was banging some of the
girls. So,
Roland's like, "I'm done with this. I
quit."
We went from very first day counting
$25,000 to $50,000 a day to over 100
130,000 dollars a day bringing in
profits. So, we're walking in with 100
150,000
a day, and the banks are freaking out.
Within weeks, the banks are like, "Uh
yeah, uh we can't do business with you
no more.
Come get your money." Somebody put us on
game like, "Start having a Brinks truck.
Have the bank that you're dealing with
have them come pick up the money so they
see the business there's a location, and
it doesn't look like you're selling on
the corner."
That saved us.
So, we were able to start putting money
in the bank. At first, we were putting
every penny in the bank because it's
legit. We wanted to claim every penny.
And then, we started to learn to not put
every penny in there. It was legit.
Legal. We had attorneys writing up the
business things, doing all our
paperwork, accountants in line to take
our money. Nobody had a problem. Nobody
cared.
Wide open. Now, everybody wanted to be
involved once we started making money.
Everybody. like literally
one guy from down south has his two guys
show up with a briefcase handcuffed to
one of the guys
slot full of cash. We were making so
much money
and to the point where we were bringing
in $4 million a month in cash. In my
height I was getting around probably
800, somewhere in there, thousand a
month.
At the beginning
I played a day-to-day role
of open make sure the doors are open,
the doctors were there, they needed what
they needed, any supplies, stuff like
that. Uh once weeks, months, about a
month in, once I realized that we had a
office manager and we had it set up
everything like that, my day-to-day role
was not
nothing. We were talking about going to
Georgia because what we wanted to do was
shorten the drive down even more.
Florida was becoming a hot spot and we
wanted out of there. The deal was that I
was supposed to be a percentage of every
clinic. Well, I found out Zach was doing
it behind my back and was bringing
somebody else in and I was going to be
cut out through somebody really close.
And cuz he'd already took money from
somebody else and promised him, so that
was their deal.
So, I was like, "Well, that's fine. I'm
going to do my own operation." So, I
offered Roland a percentage owner and
opening up pain clinics for me and doing
it the right way, that I was walking
away from Zach.
So,
Roland likes to do things right. He
wasn't never been in trouble, never
nothing. He um
agreed to come on board.
And so, we started to I started
investing money into researching and the
laws and stuff and he was running the
whole deal and we started to build an
empire. I was the only one that backed
it with funds. Hundreds of thousands. We
came up with Atlanta Medical Group. It
was going to be more downtown, but we
ended up doing a north side off 75 in
Acworth, Cartersville area.
And it was a nice building. Uh we called
it Atlanta Medical Group, AMG, like the
Mercedes.
That was our logo. I had it
professionally done up done to the T
like a real medical place really nice
and I was not going to cut costs
nowhere. I wanted to be top-notch the
right stuff right everything did it all
the right way so we set everything up
and our operation wasn't
crazy. We didn't have lines. We didn't
have people wrapped around anything. We
didn't have to have security like that.
We didn't have to have none of that. And
that's the difference between running
one where you don't have a partner as a
drug dealer business owner. Our goal was
just to open up three or four in Atlanta
and we were moving out to Hollywood. We
were moving to Missouri
Texas. We were had attorneys working on
all over the place. We had a little
harder time opening because um the
patients knew that I didn't play the
same game that Zach did. So, I had to
like almost start over on patients. They
were trying to bribe. They were trying
to give tips. They were trying to do all
this stuff and the word got around the
drug dealers and the patients. They knew
that in order to get more pills they had
to lie and they would literally they
have videos the DEA have videos of like
them walking across the street with
crutches getting out of the car with
crutches people helping them to the door
and everything and as soon as they walk
out the door they throw the crutches in
the back of the car and get in the car
like it was nothing.
And I'm like but they lied.
They said, "Yeah, but
y'all should have known better." We had
three doctors on every day and we were
doing good. It took a while to grow. We
grew the right way.
Um all my doctors were found through
headhunters. I did not hire none of my
staff. I paid people to hire the staff.
I paid people to hire the doctors. I
brought in uh somebody named Jesse. He
was a very good business person. I
thought I could trust him. Roland was
the guy that was going to start all the
businesses all the things and then Jesse
was going to come in to oversee them
make sure that they're running right my
eyes and ears. I gave Roland 25% for
running the whole operations. Jesse
eventually bought into other 25% to
oversee my operations. I got money
coming in. I'm making tons of money. My
monthly spending is around maybe like
quarter million, $300,000 a month.
Everything's going good. Then we learn
through this whole process that the pain
clinic business is coming to an end. The
DEA and the FBI is breathing down
everybody's throats. They're starting to
pull patients over. They're starting to
harass your patients. They're starting
to do all these things. So we hired
attorneys and them to go meet with the
DEA.
To see what
how are we not in compliance? How can we
be better in compliance?
They said, "It's not our job." They're
like, "But give us the rules. Where's
the rules? We want to see what
what the rules are to this this
industry."
They said, "We don't have to do none of
that. We'll let you know when you break
them. How about that?" That's what they
told us. So I told Roland and um Jesse,
I was like, "Let's shut this business
down."
Like let's just done. And Jesse, I'll
never forget Jesse's like, "We can't do
that to the girls. They depend on this
stuff. It's how they pay their bills.
Let's just keep it open a little bit
longer because I was going to get into
the um pharmacy business.
I was going to shut all the pain clinics
down and just go straight pharmacies.
One of our pharmacist techs,
her dad
had a pharmacy, couple pharmacies,
I think in a local area. And then when
CVS and Walgreens and Rite Aid came in,
they were buying up all the
mom-and-pops. And he held out and they
paid him good money for holding out.
He's like, "Yeah." He's like, um
"I would set up shop within a block or
two of every CVS, Walgreens, or Rite Aid
and step on their toes."
He goes, "I would compete with them in
prices and everything and make all your
patients or advertise to all the pain
clinics that you will sell to uh sell
pain management management meds." And he
says, "You would be able to make enough
money off of that to give everything
away else for free to step on their
toes." So now I don't have to run this
operation no more. I just put a couple
people in there run, you know, an a
manager, a two pharmacy techs, somebody
run the front desk selling all the
supplies and stuff like a CVS, Walgreens
like that on a smaller level.
Um
and I get unlimited amount of pills. So,
I can now I can sell more pills and fill
more scripts.
Who knows how much money I was going to
make. I was planning on to start at
least 50 plus
to make them buy me out for
50 100 million dollars. I had 10
locations under contract all within
blocks of a CVS, Walgreens or
um Rite Aid.
And I had two of them that were about to
open.
And
I was doing one, you know, one or two at
a time. And then the feds came
before I could get going.
I grew up in a small town called Vero
Beach, Florida. It's known for cattle
and citrus. It was a small town, it's
about a little over a north of uh West
Palm Beach. So, back in the '80s
Miami was a hot spot for drug smuggling.
Well, once the Everglades in Miami
became really a hot spot, they fly the
planes past Miami. Tampa to Vero Beach
is straight across Florida, it's like
the cut off on the fuel support. So,
they would go down on
uh waterbed bladders. So, they would
take the bladder out of a waterbed and
fill it full of fuel
and fly down on that. They would land in
Central Florida cuz it was all cattle,
citrus. It was the middle of nowhere,
small towns. Everybody was on payroll.
You can buy everybody.
So, that was made made it such a hot
spot for drug smuggling. And that's how
like my dad and everybody else got
involved. And my dad wasn't directly
involved, they offered him. But,
everyone in his circle of friends became
drug smugglers. When I was a kid, I used
to sit behind my parents or my dad and
they'd be around campfires drinking the
old Budweiser out of a can smoking old
marbles.
And uh I remember sitting around the
campfire listening to my dad's buddies
talk about drug smuggling. And that's
what got me excited to it.
And I just remember being this little
kid sitting behind them listening to the
adults that was coolest thing ever talk
about their drug smuggling. Like started
to get into the weed business at a very
young age. 14, 15 is when all my buddies
started smoking pot. So I seen that
there was um
a market in it. Um I've been in trouble
with the law before that just doing like
regular kids stuff uh trespassing, just
fighting, doing dumb stuff like that.
But the first time I ever been arrested
was dealing with stolen property. I
ended up going to juvenile prison over
it. Late '90s, early 2000s. Like '99,
2000 somewhere in that era. My sentence
was supposed to be a level six program
which was supposed to be like six to
eight months in Martin County boot camp.
Um I ended up
having a hard time. Like it was really
really rough. I go into this prison
system that where they're all called
state babies.
So they're raised by the state.
Dad's in prison, mom's a prostitute in
the streets, grandma wants nothing to do
with them. Their dates came and gone.
They don't care about nothing. So if
they see you have visits, get
commissary, uh a family and stuff, like
they just do everything they can to ruin
it. And they just run around and try to
up each other on violence and just doing
the craziest things for no odd reason. I
was at the level eight in Okeechobee,
Florida and um
I remember us walking our unit was
called for chow. And I remember we were
going to the main line to go eat dinner.
And we went by this other unit and for
no odd reason this other kid just picked
up a brick and started smashing this
other kid in the head. And I think the
first hit like kind of knocked him out.
And he was just on top of him just
smashing his head in. And there's two
female staff and they didn't even know
what to do. They didn't want to touch
him. So this kid's just getting his
head. And all the kids are just like
standing around laughing like it was a
joke. And I ended up finding out later
he did it because
they the other kids dared him to do
something or whatever. Literally just
smashed his head in. I ended up catching
seven or nine more uh battery charges
while I was in. So I went to three
different juvenile prisons. And I was
not able to uh work my way out. I ended
up timing myself out. Once I turned 18,
I um kind of like settled in where
nobody messed with me. And then I ended
up getting out right before I was 19
years old. They released me cuz I was
going to age out. The state doesn't do
anything for you. They don't give you no
help, no nothing. They literally just
kick you out and say, "Hope you do
good." Like literally you walk out the
gates, no help, no money, no nothing. Um
it's set up for everybody to fail. It's
up to you. I went through this stage of
this juvenile thing where I came home I
was like, "I'm never breaking the law
again. If prison's like this, I want
nothing to do with it." 6-8 months goes
by, you're living life, you forget. Just
like an ex. It was really toxic, wasn't
good, but you always give it that next
shot after some time. You forget about
all the bad.
So, my friends graduated from doing
smoking pot to cocaine.
There was like a drought going on or
something. I didn't know much about the
coke business, but my buddies were
complaining. My next door neighbor was
this female when I lived with my
brother, and this guy would come over
all the time. And I never forget he
drove this Dodge like on 26's, a truck.
And I'm just like dope boy written all
over it. And I was like, "Hey man, can I
talk to you?" And he's like, "Yeah." So,
I hit him up. And I was like, "You know,
what's you know, I noticed that you
know, I I can tell what [clears throat]
you're into." And he's like, "Yeah,
what's up? What what do you need?" I'm
like, "My boys want a eight ball."
So, I get it. I take it to them. They're
like, "Holy this is good. Like this is
fire. Like you can get this, we want
more." So, I gave them some more and I'm
thinking like, "Why am I doing this for
free? It wouldn't hurt to make a few
extra dollars. Like I'm struggling."
What I did was I took an eight ball and
I put a little bit of cut on it, short
the bags. I made 4 g out of 3 and 1/2.
So, I made an extra 50 bucks. I did that
twice within a couple hours. I was
selling ounces by the end of the month.
And you got to remember, timing's
everything. So, I have some of the best
product. My prices are great.
And it's unlimited.
And there's a drought. So, all my
competition right now can't find nothing
really. One thing led to another and it
just continued and then, you know, me
thinking
like, "Ah, it'll be fine. I'm only going
to do it for a short period of time. Th-
This is not going to be something I do a
long period, just short." It's like an
addiction, grabs you.
Gets really addicted then money starts
coming in and you're like, "Yeah, yeah,
we'll let let's just make
30,000.
Then let's make 50,000." The money is
not as so addictive as the lifestyle,
being involved in everything, the power
is what I call it. Within like the first
3 months I started pushing kilos. I
started at the very bottom, I was
pushing kilos. Some months I can make
75,000. I'd say 35 to 75,000 depending
on how much product I was able to get. I
had a big clientele where I was like a
high-end people where I was selling
grams and eight balls. Like a good month
and everybody paid me and I didn't get
shorted or somebody get busted or get
hit with my products, I can make $75,000
a month easily. I would literally call
my guy up and be like, "Hey, listen, I
need to get up with you." When I say get
up with you, that means I'm ready to
re-up. Once they leave, I break it up,
put it in a package and then I would
call them back and be like, "Hey, where
are you at?" And then I would drop it
off or have one of my guys drop it off.
It's a simple process. It's not as
complicated as they make it as like in
the movies and stuff. There was a family
in Florida, I think
Port Saint Lucie or something, off the
side of the Florida Turnpike a whole
family was executed. Husband, wife, and
the two kids, a Mexican family.
And rumors had it he stole like 60 kilos
from the Mexican cartel. Once that
happened, which was crazy, like my
connect and all them disappeared.
So I was like, "What in the world?" Like
so when something big like that happens
and you understand how the game works,
you get the hell out of town cuz the
heat's coming. So I was here I am
pushing three to five keys
sometimes
a week, sometimes a month depending on
like how cuz I mean my connects would I
mean my clients would go elsewhere if I
couldn't get it in right amount of time
or whatever. One would be good, one
would be garbage, they would put just
coke on top, re-press it. And I'm like,
this is a re-press. But I was so
desperate, I was buying this stuff and I
was losing. I was losing my clientele
because of the quality, whatever they
choose to cut it with, they mix it uh so
they can stretch the product. So you
take a kilo, turn into a kilo and a
quarter or kilo and a half, and then
they put it back in a press and re-press
it. Getting a uh um a kilo from actual
like Columbia or straight from the main
source,
they come with like a thick rubber that
can seal. So think of like my um
truck inner tube. So inner tubes to a
bicycle, but semis, they're really,
really thick. Like you literally have to
take a razor knife and cut it two or
three times. And they vacuum seal it
with that first, and then they wrap it
with the tape with the label on the top
of it. So when you get one that actually
has that like
thick rubber like inner tube like
sealing on it, you know you got a real
brick. And the stamps
also,
if you go and look at pictures, you'll
see like the stamp is like rounded when
it goes down. When they stamp it down,
they're kind of like rounded. And they
have like a wood grain look into it,
like a mesh.
Um re-presses are not going to have
that. I'm paying 28, 32,000 dollars a
brick at this point. I'm making no
money. And it's not even that good. At
the very beginning when I was in Mexico,
I was paying around 18 five.
And that was a really good price. Went
to like 22, 23 pretty quick, but then it
kind of capped out. I think most I paid
was like 25 at times. I gave up on
United States. I realized I wasn't going
to find it. Nobody wanted to give up
their people.
Um people hold onto it or they're just
lying.
So I was like, well, let's go back to
the 80s. Um everybody was getting from
Bahamas. My family had a house in
Bahamas. I didn't go to the island my
family has a house on. I stayed away
from there. I went to Freeport, which is
Lucaya. It's a tourist spot. I started
talking to some sources I know, and
they're like, bro, dude, like I know
people that are getting 50, 60, 100
kilos out of there in shipments. Like
it's there.
So I was like, so they're really like
smuggling is a thing there? Like, Jason,
it's never ended.
Just remember there's more drugs in the
United States than there was in '80s cuz
there's more population now, more drug
use.
He's like, so how do you think it gets
here? The smuggling, it's easy part I
feel like. Finding the connect has been
the hardest part of all.
I was like, well, I'm not giving up.
There was this guy. He kept like
strolling the block on Lakaya. Kept
riding around. We see him all the time.
So, we're at the restaurant hanging out
talking to him and I'm like, man, why is
it so hard to find stuff here? And he's
like, I don't know what you're talking
about. Like, not you know, didn't know
if we were agents or what. And there was
this room, this door, and everybody kept
coming in and out of it. And I'm like,
what's back there? And he's just like,
what do you mean? I'm like, what's back
there? Why do people keep coming in and
out? And he goes, you police? I said,
man, I empty everything. I'm like,
I ain't nothing, dude. So, Bohemians are
not allowed to gamble. There's casinos
on the island, but the Bohemians are not
allowed to.
So, he had all the underground gambling.
So, he had all these locations and he
had all these little back back rooms
that had like slot machines and all this
stuff and he was running this
underground gambling thing for the
locals.
And uh so, I was like, so, you know
people?
He goes, maybe. I think I paid 13 five
for it. I was like, they're going for 32
back at home. I said, that's a good
profit and I don't even got to do
nothing. I can sell bricks and make good
money. I was like, listen, I want five
10 out of time.
He said, not a problem. There's probably
15 20 other people over here doing the
same thing. Like, once you start going
over there enough, you start realizing
you're looking around like, holy
Like, these are same faces here every
time. Like, what are they doing? He's
like, what do you think they're doing?
The same thing as you. I ended up
getting a source in the Coast Guard. I
grew up with somebody.
I kind of had somebody ask questions on
like, where are y'all patrolling? What's
going on? Somebody close. And I was
paying him to ask questions as a close
friend. If it was really good
information, he'd be like, hey, listen,
we're patrolling we're next couple weeks
we're going to be patrolling off of
Freeport. We're surveillance in there.
We know some stuff going on. That was a
$5,000 payout. I would at least make it
worthwhile like, thank you so much. This
is 2006-7
era, you know, time 2005-7.
Um, at this point we're moving five or
10 at a time. I had custom dive tanks
made.
So, what we do is we take the dive tank
right off the bottom cuz you got these
little black plastic caps that go in and
lock them into the little things.
And we'd pull them off and had a machine
shop cut them precise. And then they
would weld this thing in and put these
little O-rings and all this stuff and
these little pins. So, we'd pop them
apart and then they weld a bladder in
there.
So, you can leave about that much out
the top and still have air and the gauge
would say that it had so much pressure
in it and you could shh shh
and have air.
And we would be able to fit um three to
five kilos depending on how I broke them
up and shoved them in each one of them.
I known somebody that was a drug
smuggler like when I was a kid, so I hit
him up. I was like, "How do you do it?
Like, what's going on?" I I knew I could
trust him. He says, "If you're going to
do small amounts, do not hide it in your
boat. Don't do nothing. Just put it like
in a in a net bag.
Put a little bit of weight in it." He
says, "If you start seeing them come in,
throw that thing nonchalant over side of
the boat. Don't put enough weight in it
to where it'll go straight to the
bottom."
He says,
um or not enough weight to where it it
floats. You want it the current to to
carry it as far as possible
to where it doesn't just go straight to
the bottom. You got to remember the
Coast Guard
and US Customs are not going to pull you
over in the middle of the ocean. They're
going to wait until you come into out of
international waters because they know
where you're going, right? United
States. Well, once you get out of
international waters back in United
States water, the water's only like
60-ft deep.
So, you know, if you throw it over and
go straight to the bottom, what are they
going to do?
They're going to dive down there and
find it. So, I would come across like I
was fishing the banks all day, not even
go to the islands where it showed on
radar that I was going and I was going
to swing in
and dive down, grab the dope. I don't
know if you ever heard of they're called
weed lines where the two currents come
together and it pushes all the trash in
the ocean into like these weed lines
where the two currents come together. I
would have a tracker on the boat.
And my guy that was fishing these weed
lines would be out there just come out
and start fishing all day long. He knew
what day I would come back.
And I would come and once he seen me
activate that
beeper, the tracking device, he would
see it on his thing, okay, this is where
he's at. Now I would just ride by, not
stop, just throw the dope over. And the
beacon would be there. He would pick up
the boat dope and keep fishing
throughout rest of day and I'd come
right on in empty loaded. When they're
watching the satellites and the radar,
they just see a boat going out 10, 15,
20 miles, fishing all day just like
everybody else.
They don't see him intercepting a boat
out there where two boats pull up on it.
He didn't go to Bahamas. So, they're not
watching him.
When I was in the cocaine business, I
literally lived like a bum. I would have
like a decent vehicle. I lived in a
small house.
Because you have to play the game.
How am I going to be living in something
big and don't have nothing to show how I
got it? That's the best way to get
gossip and people to uh talking about
you. And I just did a podcast with the
law enforcement guy.
And one of the main reasons why they
never really came after me is because I
was so quiet. I wasn't loud. Somebody
was always willing to take that
spotlight from me. So, I never spent no
money really, didn't really do much. I
had a lot of hidden investments, doing
stuff like that behind the scenes. I
invested into uh medical marijuana and
uh weed operation out in Colorado and
California. So, we are making pretty
good money at the time. But, when I got
out of the game, it was so depressing
because
you don't realize
the excitement that's real and how you
had that needle in your arm stuck the
whole time until you get out of it. Now
all of a sudden your phone's not blowing
up. You're not the popular guy.
You ain't cool no more.
Somebody else done took your place. When
I tell you the day you get out of the
game, it's like within 24 to 48 hours.
Um
Who are you again? Jason who?
And it was kind of depressing. I mean,
it was days I couldn't get off the couch
cuz
I was so addicted to making money. Now
I'm not making that kind of money. Like
I had this little loan sharking thing,
some other stuff going on, but it wasn't
until I got in the pain clinic where I
can actually
be like, "Hey, you know, where are you
getting your money?" Oh, I have this
pain clinic.
You know, it the money's in the bank
now.
I didn't buy stuff cash. I was swiping
on a card. Swipe, swipe, swipe. There we
go. It was the root of all evil. That's
when we started buying Ferraris,
Lamborghinis, you know, 20, 30 thousand
dollar nights in strip clubs, landing
helicopters wherever we wanted to drop
them at. My average monthly spending
between all my bills and operations was
250, 350 thousand dollars a month.
Just to survive, just the racing alone.
I mean,
we were going through so many race
motors and race cars. I mean, that race
car was a half million dollar race car,
a drag car, six second outlaw. And it's
just JV Racing Motorsports.
Uh we didn't have no advertisement on
it. We had a half million dollars in the
car and hadn't even made it
down the track yet. The motor alone was
101,000.
Just 100,000 and you every so many
passes, it cost another 14,000 just to
freshen it up after so many passes.
Tires, this, that. My daughter was born
8/13/08.
So,
beginning to '09-ish, somewhere in
there, I was done.
I was It was over with. I had enough
money.
And I was just at the point where I was
just like,
"It's it's not worth it." Once I had my
daughter and I come home and I held her
after that last go-around, I told myself
I was done. How much did you have at
that point? It's hard to say because
you got assets, cash,
bank accounts in the millions. I had
millions.
The day the George brothers showed up is
when our investigation started. 2000 end
of 9 beginning of 10. They put a task
force on us.
I walked away from Zach. I started the
Georgia thing and moved on.
Was it months later
the George all three pain clinics in
Florida got shut down by the DEA.
I'll never forget
I was going to get pump gas
and Zach calls me. He was like, "Hey,
um
is your pain card working?" And I'm
like, "Why?" And he's like, "Dude, I
tried to use mine this morning and it's
not working. I can't get no way to
return my phone calls."
And we haven't talked in a while. Like
we're not friends. Then we find out that
the Florida clinics got hit and they
seized all our assets. All our
businesses, bank accounts, everything
was shut down. I really have no money in
cash. I invested into all these other
businesses. I've forked out tons of
money in these pharmacies, the medical
marijuana, the fertilizer company. I've
got money out everywhere. I had $300 in
my pocket.
Atlanta Medical Group, every penny went
into the bank. They seized that. So
Florida seized that because it was tied
to Jacksonville. And I didn't want to
tell nobody in Georgia. All my things I
only brought my office manager and I was
like, "This is what the deal is. So
we're going to start up another bank
account."
Luckily, we had enough pills in there
and everything going on to where we
could stay afloat. We just got a
shipment of pills in. They were bought
and paid for.
So the clinic is still operating. People
are paying in cash. So at the end of the
day, we have a pharmacy full of pills.
Doctors are writing scripts. We at the
end of the day, we got a stack of cash.
I already hired big time attorneys.
They're all telling me that um
indictments will be coming. They didn't
arrest nobody when they raided all the
clinics in Florida. Yeah, I finally get
this good attorney and he goes meets
with the feds.
Um he comes back and he says,
"You're going to go to prison for a long
time."
He said, "No matter what you do." And
I'm like, "Really?" He goes, "Yeah.
They're going to make a political
statement out of y'all."
Am I
Okay.
So, what's my options? He says, you can
shut your Atlanta operation down and
everything else and
um just wait for them or you can keep
that operation up and running and the
amount of time you're going to get down
here and they'll run that concurrent and
nothing else will happen to you and just
stack as much money as you can to make
sure everybody's taken care of.
This If I'm not going to get no more
trouble, it's let's let's double down.
Let's go as hard as we can stack.
So, that was the operation and um
I couldn't believe it. They let us go
for another like 16 months.
And um they finally raided my Georgia
clinics.
When we got indicted,
the DEA said that how they did it was is
first they looked at the top 10
prescribing doctors in the nation.
Between Vinnie Colangelo, me and Zach
and the George brothers, we had probably
the top 25 or 30. So, that's how big
they had to go to figure out where it
ends. We went to the top. Now, we're the
top purchasers of oxycodone in the
nation. The Florida case was my problem.
Florida case was the bad one. That was
the one that I didn't think I would that
I was impossible to win.
So, Florida case is the one that had all
the drug dealers, the bribes, all the
bad stuff, everything you can think
about. It was just absolutely bad.
Everybody's cooperating.
Everybody. Doctors are already took plea
deals. Zach's cooperating. Everybody's
cooperating. Everybody's admitting that
it was run bad and everybody knew. My
good friend Brooke Brooke was my
personal attorney on all my legal drug
stuff. She told us, you don't talk, I'll
get you out of anything you want. Just
shut the hell up. And um I'm complaining
to her. I'm like, Brooke,
these attorneys this, attorneys that.
And she finally was like, listen, Jason,
I don't mess with the feds and there's a
reason why I don't play with these
people. She says, I'll take your case
and your case only.
I have a good mentor that will help me
through this. So, Brooke takes the case
and it's just absolutely horrible. It's
so bad.
And um we get into it, we fight.
There's times that she was in tears
begging my family to for me to take a
plea deal at times because she didn't
want to watch me go away for life cuz it
was a life sentence if I was found
guilty. Cuz there was
deaths involved, OD'ing that I wasn't
charged with, but it was just going to
be bad. It was going to be setting an
example. I'm fighting both cases at the
same time, right? I wasn't even arrested
for Florida yet. I got arrested in
Georgia first.
While I was getting pulled over and and
tracked by the cops and they pull me
over, I'm on the phone with Brooke like,
"Brooke, they got us." I said, "There's
so many agents here got us pulled over
right now." I get bond, I'm out, I'm at
a strip club doing work. My phone won't
stop blowing up and the family look at
it says, "You've just been indicted in
Florida." Trucking conspiracy oxycodone
um and money laundering. They're all the
same. She built the case off of painting
this picture that everybody was looking
at so much time that they would say and
do whatever it took to get out of
trouble with Zach's phone calls. Zach is
talking crazy on the jail phone calls.
Talking about I'll say and do whatever
it takes for me to come home. I don't
care what I got to say, whatever they
want me to say, I'm going to say it cuz
I'm coming home. I ain't doing all this
time.
And we got those phone calls and Brooke
was like, "Let's do this."
Uh after a month-long trial, uh seven
people cooperated against me and got on
the stand. Um Brooke absolutely just
obliterated them during the trial with
the with the recordings and everything
else. They all took plea deals. He
messed up. He was supposed to only get a
small amount of time, but playing the
recordings, he got more time. So, I was
found not guilty.
And that's unheard of. I was supposed to
go to trial 2 months later.
They postponed it because they didn't
have no witnesses. They didn't have
nobody cooperating against me yet. Jesse
finally folds.
My office manager folds. So, I go to
trial.
I was found guilty. I got 15 years in
federal prison.
So, I appeal it on double jeopardy cuz
they were both they intertwined. I got
denied all the way through until I got
out.
Purdue Pharma is the company that
created OxyContin. It's owned by the
Sackler family. And people don't really
understand that. They think that it's
only people like dope boys in on the
streets or drug dealers like me.
But no, it's not. It's people in suits,
people in ties. Pill mills are an issue
in the US is because their sole purpose,
the ones that were doing it illegally
and pushing the pills, were doing it
just to put drugs on the street and they
were getting in the wrong hands with the
wrong people. People were getting
medication uh large amounts and the
doctors wouldn't monitoring it right.
So, they were getting addicted. And once
they get addicted, they were having to
go and sell them on the streets and lie,
steal, and do stuff to continue their
addiction. And that's why it became a
problem. Purdue Pharma lobbied Congress
to pretty much exempt them from
prosecution. They pay fines, we do time.
Purdue Pharma and these other companies,
they knew it was an issue, they knew
they lied, they knew they manipulated.
You can read the reports. And they did
it for the sole purpose like a drug
dealer on the corner, like Frank Lucas
did here in New York. They sent their
main guys down to educate our doctors
and they left that part out. They say,
"Order for this to pass, it has to be
under a certain percentage of
dependency." Which was a lie. They're
telling our doctors, "Well, if they're
saying this, you prescribe them that."
Like on the bottle it says, "This is how
you prescribe it. This is what you do."
Doctors only know what they're being
told from these big companies. Most of
these doctors were set up. They were
doing exactly what they were taught and
told and then they got prosecuted
because people were getting in you know,
it was ruining their lives like
gambling, sex, everything else. And
let's just say that
everybody else
paid the price for their their profits.
And instead of going to the source, the
head that's created this issue, which is
Purdue and distributors, people that was
teaching our doctors and telling them
what to do,
and we're the last
They can't go no higher than us to just
to tell America,
"Look what we're doing.
We're fixing the problem.
Just like the cartels.
They take one head out knowing that the
vice president of that cartel is going
to become the head of the cartel.
Knowing it ain't going to do nothing,
but they get to do this nice press. Look
what we got.
Look, we just took out the three biggest
pain clinic pill mills. But meanwhile,
there's still 600 pain clinics still
owned and operated in in the southern
region
when I was going to trial. I knew it was
really bad, that's why I didn't want to
get into it. I knew it was really bad,
but then at same time it's like they're
allowing you to do it. It's like
casinos. It's like gambling is a
horrible thing. We allow it.
It's very addictive. People lose
everything, destroy their lives, but
they still allow them to do it. Is it
right? No. But is it legal? It's legal.
It's a moral thing. Right is a moral
thing. You know, it's like
you know, this person has addictive
personality. Why would you do drugs
around him and taunt him? You know what
I'm saying? That's right or wrong.
Legal is something that
I'm allowed to do it,
but it's not really right. Like
we shouldn't be doing these things. Just
cuz it's legal doesn't mean it's right.
You know what they were doing? Investing
their time with our doctors. Making sure
the doctors were happy. Making sure the
doctors were prescribing. Making sure
that any questions they had were
answered. The doctors
you got to remember, they were
their own people. 1099. They were
you know, subcontractors.
So, if they wanted to meet with the
reps, that's their 222 form DEA
registration number. That is their
business.
It's just a game.
It's the code. It's the game. It's You
can't get in this game and get mad
because they paid and they they got the
connects, they got the pool. I mean, you
can still get OxyContin. And now you're
getting fentanyl from the doctors. What
they did was is they made doctors not
want to prescribe it. But they're still
doing it. It's still out there. It's
just doctors are scared because they
were getting them so much time. They
changed some of the rules like in-house
dispensary, you can only dispense like 3
days at a time or whatever, but you
still run a pain clinic and write
scripts and make money. Nobody cares
about your health. When they allowed me
to do what I did, me, Zach, Vinnie,
George brothers allowed us to do what we
did,
it showed America that it didn't care
about
your life at all. Doesn't They don't
care.
Um they allowed criminals like me cuz
I'm a criminal. I'm not going to lie.
I've been a criminal my whole life. When
they allowed somebody like me to do this
and know that I was a drug smuggler and
I was a known criminal,
um somebody's been to prison,
what makes you believe that that's
changed their thoughts and how they
believe and think?
Think about that.
When COVID hit, they locked all the
prison systems down.
Once they did that and COVID was so bad
in the prisons, so bad.
It was weeks later, they called a town
hall and they're like, "Okay guys,
listen. Anybody meets these
requirements, we got to start filling
out this paperwork. You're probably
going to go home to home confinement for
a short period of time." So, I stay out
for 3 and 1/2 years on home confinement.
Trump did the thing during COVID, I got
out on home confinement and then Biden
gave me a clemency. I got some really,
really high connects and um fam.
Um so, I was introduced to somebody that
is really high ranking in the prison
reform thing. Clemency got rid of my
prison sentence. So, no longer on ankle
monitor, may be able to do what I want
to do,
um travel. I was on probation afterwards
a financial because they hit me with a
$4.3 million fine.
You know, they monitor my finances
pretty regularly. They said that I
buried $8.8 million and then they
renegotiate down to $3.9 [clears throat]
million. So, I'll tell you this.
I didn't even know the amount. So, how
do do they know it? They take a
percentage of what income comes in. So,
it can vary. It's been as low as
um
$50 or $25 a month all the way up to
$250 a month.
It's never going to get paid. It's I
don't have no victims. It's court fines.
So, I did all eight of the time getting
bond and everything is around eight
years.
I do speeches. I have 10 toes podcasts
that I do. And I just started my new
clothing line. It's called Dope Boy
Empire. The ex-agent in my case, Mike,
we started the pig and the plug.
He's the pig, the cop, I'm the plug. We
I started going on their uh law
enforcement podcast. Um Anti-Heroes.
And um he has Copville. I run a small
construction business doing remodels and
stuff like that because that's what, you
know,
I wasn't allowed to do much when I was
in home confinement getting off. So, I'm
just getting into bigger things, but
that is the money maker right now.
Knowing the outcome, I wish I would have
went harder at the game.
I would have made more money and put
more money away knowing the outcome. How
are you going to protect your daughter?
What what are you going to teach her?
It's scary you say that. I have
conversations with her
of truth. I don't hide nothing from her.
That's a sore subject because
the destruction and pain that I've done
helped other people
is my worst fear.
That that's going to come back and bite
me and that's going to be my thing. And
only thing I can do is continue to
preach to her and explain to her my
flaws, what I lost out on,
what it's done to other people. Look at
these people that made bad choices and
went down the road of drugs. And who can
I blame? Myself. Only thing I can tell
people is
for all the young people out there,
um
y'all got to quit idolizing
these stories on on Hollywood and these
rappers and everything else because
it's all fun and games till you get the
handcuffs put on you.
I was that young guy that was watching
those movies and the stories and seeing,
oh, they only got 10 years, they moved
tons of kilos of heroin, cocaine, and
all this stuff.
Oh, I can do that. I just justify it.
I'd just be like, "Oh, millions for 5
years? Like, oh, sign me up." Guys,
that's not the truth.
Hi, I'm a producer on How Crime Works.
If you enjoyed this video, then please
subscribe and comment below with more
ideas of topics you'd like us to cover
in this series.